

# DAVID VILELA

Despite I started my carrer from a purely scientific and academic perspective, after my PhD I decided to shift my focus towards more applied fields, since I felt I was more interested in the practical application parts of problem-

I consider myself an IT enthusiast, and love understanding and automating things. I am particularly interested in new technologies, especially Machine Learning, Distributed Ledger Technologies and Security. I'm a fan of the aerospatial industry, Physics and Mathematics, music, design, LEGO blocks and I'm fascinated by the human brain and how things work.

where every member must take ownership on their projects and be able to work without close supervision. Currently I work for an automotive research center where I'm implementing a sensor managing and recording platform to generate training data for machine learning algorithms. Recently I've started taking a DevOps role, learning about Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins and the CI/CD cycle, as well as server managing.

Previously I've worked on the development of efficient, real-time collision detection algorithms, multibody simulators applied to virtual assembly and vehicle, the-loop platforms. I have also designed and developed haptic interface hardware and its corresponding control

Teaching at the university for four years and writing scientific papers helped me to improve my communication skills, and since I've always loved explaining things to others as well as divulgation, I keep trying to make my tiny contribution through my Youtube

## **CONTACT & MORE**

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Machine Learning Platform Engineer 2020 - Present

CTAG, Automobile Technological Center of Galicia

Developing a sensor recording, managing, syncing and decoding platform to generate training data for autonomous vehicle machine learning algorithms. Learning DevOps.

#### 2019 - 2020 Research Support Technician

Mechanical Engineering Laboratory, University of A Coruña

Researched and validated a volumetric force model based on sphere discretizations from the Computer Graphics Group. Wrote two research papers based on my dissertation's results and those validations.

#### 2014 - 2018 Predoctoral Researcher & PhD Teaching Assistant

Mechanical Engineering Laboratoryy, University of A Coruña

Researched and implementated a multibody real time simulator capable of handling conforming contacts using a precise collision detection algorithm and a volumetric force model. Developed a VR haptic feedback glove device, from electronics design to control software. Teached Solid Works and CAD. Colaborated with the Computer Graphics Group in the University of Bremen during an insternational stay.

#### 2012 - 2014 Research Assistant

Mechanical Engineering Laboratory, University of A Coruña Developed a real-time multibody vehicle simulator for hardware-inthe-loop platforms to assess vehicle dynamics behaviour. Developed a multibody algorithm benchmarking and ranking website oriented towards international scientific collaboration.

### **EDUCATION**

2014 - 2018	PhD in Industrial and Naval Engineering
-------------	---

University of A Coruña

2012 - 2013 Industrial and Naval Technologies Research M. Eng

University of A Coruña

2003 - 2011 Industrial Engineering B. Eng + M. Eng

University of A Coruña

## COURSES, CERTIFICATES AND ACTIVITIES

DevOps with Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Git and CI/CD, Coursera 2021

Hands-On Test Driven Development with Python, Coursera

Jenkins, From Zero To Expert: Become A Jenkins Master, Coursera

SOLID and Clean Code principles. Write quality code, Coursera

C1 Certificate in Advanced English, Cambridge School 2014

Introduction to Artificial Intelligence, Stanford University Online 2011

Introduction to Machine Learning, Stanford University Online

Child Education and Support Volunteering, Nepal Sonríe NGO

Coastal Skipper, Nautical and Fishing School of Ferrol 2003

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

My current main technologies are C++ and Python, and I regularly work with Bash, Flask, HTML/CSS and JavaScript, In the past I've used Fortran, Matlab/Octave and Django. I've been developing mostly under GNU/Linux, where I am the most comfortable, but I spent my two first research years in Windows and I have also developed under Mac OS for a few

I usually fiddle with Raspberry Pis, and from time to time also with Arduinos, ESP32 and ESP8266. I've also developed some small home projects using Python, Bash, JavaScript/Node, Django, REST, Websockets, SQLite, HTML/CSS and Qt among others. I'm familiar with web development, graphic design, 3D modeling, scientific writing and audio/video edition.